and then we will open up for questions.
So, Brian, go ahead.
>> Yeah, thank you. Um, obviously we're uh
very very excited. Uh, Jeremy uh is a uh
tremendous person. Uh really really
really impressed with him on his uh 30
visit. um his energy, his character, his
makeup of who he is as a person and um
uh and uh you know a great football
player, a real productive player, had a
lot of success, comes from a great
program with a lot of history and
tradition and um with that I'll open up
for any questions.
>> How does he fit into your offense, you
think?
>> I'm sorry.
>> How does he fit into this offense? Yeah,
I think um you know, we like his
versatility, his flex to play inside and
outside. Um and um you know, when we get
him here, certainly we see a guy that
that can play inside and outside and
ultimately when we start practicing,
we'll we'll see where um where he fits
best with the other receivers.
>> How much did his ability to return kicks
and also the ability to maybe take jet
sweeps and other things like that after
the catch and after the run kind of
contr you guys wanting to go in there?
Yeah, I think the the flexibility is
certainly um always attractive when you
got a guy that could have multiple
roles, when you can help on special
teams in in all four phases and then
certainly when you have the f
flexibility to be able to put them in
the back field, move them around so the
defense really can't focus in on one
area. And I think uh more than anything
else, he's a clutch player. You know,
he's made a lot of big catches for
Alabama uh in critical moments. and you
see um you know that's that's where they
were going with the ball and and you
always want that in a player.
>> You mentioned he's a tremendous person.
When you guys posted him here for a talk
visit, what did you learn about him that
you maybe didn't know previously?
>> You know, just just his passion, um his
faith, his commitment. Uh those those
really stood out to me. I mean, he's a
he's a strong willed individual who has
tremendous faith and as a per and in
what he wants and what he looks for. So,
I was really really impressed with the
maturity of how he he looked at things.
>> When you're looking to add to a position
like wide receiver, how much are you
considering the traits of the guys, but
also the traits of the guys you already
have and how they fit together? And how
do you think he complements DK and P?
>> Yeah, I think with with every pick, you
really try to look at do they fit the
Steeler way? Do they fit the philosophy
of of the Rooney family and coach
McCarthy and certainly Omar. I mean, I
think that's with every pick. You try to
bring in the right people. Uh, you want
to have high character people and
obviously good football players. So, I
think that's with all the picks.
>> How much do you view his size as an
asset in a physical division like the
AFC North?
>> Yeah, the uh the AFC North is a physical
division as we all know. But I think
certainly there's there's there's real
productive players. You know, I think
more importantly than size, it's um you
know, what does your tape look like? Can
you make plays? And and this young man
made a lot of plays in critical downs.
>> When you're evaluating a player who has
so much production and experience at the
college level, how does that aid in your
process of understanding exactly what
you're going to be getting?
>> Well, I you know, you've heard a few uh,
you know, great coaches. I know Jimmy
Johnson years ago, he would, he had a
line, the the best measure of future
success is past success. So, I I
certainly think if guys are are doing it
at a high level at a program like
Alabama in a really competitive division
on a national stage, usually you feel
good about when they get here. Now,
obviously, it's an adjustment and what
you do in college doesn't guarantee you
anything at this league at this level.
You have to go prove it every day. The
one thing I do feel good about is I
think Jeremy's mindset is that he'll go
prove it every day. Now, ultimately when
he gets here, we'll see, you know, we'll
see where he fits and how he's he's
going to help the team and and you know
when he'll be able to help the team. So
that's there's a long way to go from
that
yesterday for receivers in the first
round.
>> I'm sorry. Five receivers went yesterday
in the first round. You guys were
obviously hunting receiver. A couple
more receivers went today.
>> How fluid and deep did you deem to be
that class? And how close was he to the
pack that went yesterday?
>> Yeah, I mean I I don't want to share
where we had guys or where the where the
rankings were. I just know obviously
Jeremy was someone that we valued and
and we're very very happy to have him.
>> Has run the ball somehow
things of that nature. Uh do you guys
value
gadgety type stuff for lack of a better
word? Uh philosophically
>> we value whatever moves the football.
So, however we got to do it, uh
certainly you're going to have your jet
sweeps and gadgets, but um you know,
he's more than that and uh we'll use
him, you know, the best way we can.
>> How would you assess his route running
at this point?
>> Yeah, I think he's he he's a good route
runner. I think he's um he understands
the route tree. I think he understands
how to create leverage, how to move
defenders. I think he he's shown an
ability to play inside and outside and I
think that's something that's really um
you know because at the end of the day
you know receivers they got to know how
to run routes and they got to get off
press and uh you know those are some
skills that he has shown.
>> He has a pretty big reputation of being
a dirty worker type you know blocking
and all that. How much did that show up
in a statement? How much was that
attractive to you when you watched him?
>> That's that's always attractive. I think
um you know you sell receivers the best
way to get you open is you got to do the
dirty work inside. So the defense has to
commit to the run. And the more you can
have those kind of roles and that
ability to u to show that you're willing
to go dig out a safety or a nickel
obviously uh that puts more stress on
the defense now because you can go up on
them.
>> Two more guys. Two more. here. Do you
have anyone you've coached in the past?
Different styles, Brian?
>> Um,
it's a good question. Um, u I'll have to
get back to you on that one.
>> Brian, in the short time you've been
here, you've added he and Pitman free
agency. How do you feel just overall
about the strength of that group?
>> Yeah, I think, you know, we're we're
excited about all our wide outs and um I
think we'll we'll have a better uh we
like the we like the players that we
have. We like the people that we have
and in in the next couple months we'll
have certainly a better feel of where
those pieces are going to fall. But
we're we're pleased with where where the
room's heading.
>> All right. Different.